Hakim Ben Hadj Brahim

 ♥ Houmet Souk, Djerba, Tunisia
 ■ bhbhakim001@gmail.com
 □ +216 27272710
 In/hakimbhb
 ■ https://hakimbhb.github.io

SUMMARY

I'm a tech enthusiast dedicated to innovation in web and mobile solutions. With expertise in Flutter, Dart, and more, I bring creativity, efficiency, and a drive for perfection to every project. Let's collaborate to create captivating digital experiences that leave a lasting impression. Your vision, my expertise – let's make it extraordinary.

EXPERIENCE

Core Product | Insight Plus | Ariana , Tunisia | May 2024 - Present

Flutter Developer Part Time | Creative Master | Egypt | October 2023 - April 2024

- \bullet Collaborated with the team to reduce app crashes by 30% by identifying and resolving critical issues in the codebase
- · Implemented optimizations, leading to a 40% increase in system efficiency and significantly improving overall app responsiveness.
- Developed and launched cross-platform mobile applications using Flutter, achieving a 30% increase in user engagement and reducing development time by 25% through effective use of Dart programming language and Firebase backend integration.

Flutter Developer - Internship | Solvers Technologies | Djerba, Houmet Souk | June 2023 - August 2023

- Crafted DeliSmart Mobile App, redefining E-commerce deliveries. Reviewed code, debugged problems, and corrected issues.
- · Analyzed existing software implementations to identify areas requiring improvement.
- · Delivered solutions for optimized delivery routes and peak productivity.
- Developed and customized over 20 reusable Flutter widgets for multiple client projects, reducing UI development time by 30%, and enhancing code reusability.
- · Developed and integrated RESTful APIs in Flutter applications to enhance data retrieval and management using tools like Postman and Retrofit.

Freelance Full Stack Developer | Self Employed | Djerba, Houmet Souk | January 2020 - Present

- · Developed tailored solutions, optimizing team efficiency by 30% and resolving 90% of issues in programs and databases.
- · Collaborated closely with clients, resulting in a 25% improvement in team efficiency and productivity.
- Facilitated effective collaboration within the team, resolving 95% of issues promptly. Applied industry best practices and creative problem-solving techniques, leading to a 25% improvement in team efficiency and productivity.

PROJECTS

Tayarh | Creativity Masters | tayarh.com | February 2024 - Present

- · Revamp UI for both driver and user apps.
- · Add new features to enhance user experience.
- Utilize VPS for hosting the entire project.
- $\bullet \;\;$ Implement Bloc pattern for improved performance.
- Integrate new features for both mobile app and admin panel using Laravel.
- Address and resolve existing issues for smoother operation.
- Enhanced application stability, leading to smoother operations and a better user experience.

Nashtari | Freelance | -- | November 2023 - January 2024

- Implement Google AdMob for effective advertising.
- Integrate payment systems for Android and iOS platforms.
- Implement Bloc pattern for efficient state management.
- Support both dark and light modes.
- Integrate with Firebase Cloud for data storage and retrieval.

Interior X | AlgoWorks | apps.apple.com/tn/app/interior-x-ai-home-design/id6468151485 | September 2023 - October 2023

- Implemented essential iOS permissions, boosting user engagement by 25%.
- Ensured compliance with Apple's standards, contributing to a 30% increase in downloads.
- Reduced app loading times by 40%, enhancing user experience and increasing retention rates by 20%.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree In Network Engineering | Higher Institute of Applied Sciences and Technology of Mateur | Bizerte, Mateur | 2024

- Video PFE (STUDY HARBOR MOBILE APP)
- https://bit.ly/4fNKZfY

High school diploma in Computer Engineering | Lycee Houmt-souk Djerba | 2021

CERTIFICATIONS

Flutter & Dart & Firebase complete development | Udemy | 2023

Git And Github | Almdrasa | 2023

Postman API Fundamentals Student Expert | Postman | 2023

 $Computer\ Science\ for\ Python\ Programming\ (Professional\ Certificate)\ |\ HarvardX\ on\ edX\ |\ 2022$

EF SET English Certificate (C1) | EF Standard English Test (EF SET) | 2022

SKILLS

Database Wizard: MySQL, SQL, Firebase, Nest Js, PostreSql

Hosting and Deployment: VPS, Hosting, CyberPanel

Problem Solver Extraordinaire

Software: Vscode, Xcode, Android Studio ,Mamp, Xampp

OS Mastery: macOS, Ubuntu, Windows

TeamWork, Communication